# **Robert Wagner** | Technical Writer

Salt Lake City, UT

rob.wagnerusa@protonmail.com | LinkedIn Profile | Portfolio Website | C. 385.495.4015

### **Professional Summary**

Dynamic 20-year background in Technical Support, Sales & Marketing, Banking, and Education.

**Technical Writer |** With 6+ years in technical case notes, I discovered that I love technical writing, and I'm good at it! I have produced 1000's of technical case notes, documentation, How-To's, Installation Guides, and Upgrade/Configuration manuals! I look forward to next steps as a Technical and Senior Technical Writer with my chosen company!

### **Skills & Experience**

- Branding | Style Guide and Technical Documentation Creation
- Coding | HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHP, XML, and RegEx
- Design Software | Adobe, Figma, and Greenshot (kind of like Snag-it)
- Project Software | Microsoft Office Word, Excel, CRM, Outlook, and PowerPoint
- Teaching | Known for my ability to Simplify complex technical concepts for customers
- Communications | Public Speaking, Presentation Design and Delivery
- High-level Communications | Professional B2B and B2C written and verbal communications
- Sample | Word Press Example Website (took about 1 hour, very simple construction co. site)
- Sample | Community volunteer <u>Emergency Preparedness Website</u> (built from scratch on Github)

## **Employment**

**Applications Support Engineer II** MVi - Millennial Vision, Inc.

2018 - Present

MVi/CDi provides SaaS Solutions for Financial Institutions and Municipalities in Electronic Content Management systems, including hardware and software deployment, configuration, and support.

- **Technical Writing** | 1,000's of technical case notes and documents produced both in complex technical resolution, SaaS Software Support, and Marketing.
- **Technical Design |** Upgraded a fillable PDF Annual Review From to an online, web-based form to serve as our Annual Review Form for the entire company
- Productivity | Completed over 30 contracts in 2023, securing \$300K+ in contract revenue, in addition to relieving front-line on complex cases and managing other projects within our IT Project Management vertical

- Productivity | Fast-paced, solutions-driven, objectives achieved. Sometimes solving 100+ tickets/month where it was common for team members to achieve between 40-60
- UX Design | Also served as a local website resource, responsible for adding documents, and managing updates with UX of website

### Recruiting Manager | Robert Half

2017

Robert Half provides talent sourcing services for Finance and Accounting roles, as well as Technical and other business process roles

#### **Assistant Branch Manager** Utah First Federal Credit Union

2016-2017

- Design | Designed a branch-specific marketing slick, and used it to prospect local dealerships
- Sales | Added 3 new dealer partners to the branch the same week and began taking applications
- Team building | Reduced branch turnover from 75% to 25% by analyzing the team's
  motivations/interests, providing regular branch snacks (on my own dime, but worth it), as well as
  a positive, upbeat attitude to help keep the team happy and engaged

#### **Field Admissions Representative** | Universal Technical Institute, Inc.

2012 - 2015

Universal Tech. provides technical career training for Automotive, Diesel, and motorsports industries.

As a Field Admissions Representative, I was invited into 50+ high schools to provide career planning presentations to classes of ~20-40 students

#### **Key Achievements:**

- **Public Relations** | Conducted over 400 interviews with students and their families to discuss their education and career path, and plan a course to help them achieve it
- Productivity | In less than 6 months, generated over \$450K in successful starts
- Productivity | The following year, generated over \$1,000,000 in successful starts
- B2B and Education industry relations | Through patience, professionalism, consistent follow up, and creativity, went from 15 accounts to over 50 accounts that I could continue to develop each year, leveraging my experience in communications, collaboration, and win/win mentality, keeping accounts engaged and active each successive year

### **Education**

BS - Web Design & Development | BYU Certificate - Web Media | BYU AS - Business | Green River College